Schaefer, Vincent; Papers ua902.010
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Environmentalism, 1940-1993; 8; 11.5 cubic ft.
  - Subject Files, 1926-1992; Undated; 8.4
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: Some Fascinating Features of the Glenville Hills," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 20)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: The Touareuna: Where we Dwell Together," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 21)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: The Valley of the Schoharie," Schaefer,Vincent J.- The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 22)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: What Have We Done to This Beautiful Land?" (Typescript), 1971 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 23)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: The Yantaputchaberg," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 24)
    - "The Founding of the Long Path," Schaefer, Vincent J.- Trail Walker, 1986 February-1986 March (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 25)
    - "Long Path of New York", Schaefer, Vincent J., 1935 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 26)
    - "A Matter of Policy", Schaefer, Vincent J.- typescript, 1984 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 27)
    - "Memorandum Relative to The Long Path of New York", Schaefer, Vincent J., 1974 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 28)
    - "The Old Maid's Woods- A Remnant of The Pine Plains", Schaefer, Vincent J., 1967; 1971-1973 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 29)
    - "Purple Mountains Majesty", Schaefer, Vincent J.- photocopied manuscript, 1991 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 30)
    - Schenectady Bird Club- brochure, 1947-1948 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 31)
    - Schenectady County Aquifer Preservation Study and Report, 1978 (Box 10 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 32)
    - Schenectady County Chamber of Commerce, Environmental Advisory Council, 1978-1979 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Schenectady County Conservation Council- report, 1932 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Schenectady County Planning Departmental Newsletter- "Planning", 1971-1974 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Schenectady Cycling Club, Constitution, 1942 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Schenectady Riverside Flood Research Committee, 1977 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Schenectady Winter Sports Club, 1931; 1935-1936; 1962; Undated (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6-7)
    - Snow Train Bulletin, 1935 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8)
    - Society for Preservation of Water Resources, Inc., 1982-1985 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9)
    - State of New York Conservation Department- map, Undated (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - Survey of History and Natural Sciences of the Five Rivers Area, 1936 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Survey of History and Natural Sciences of the Five Rivers Area- Maps and History, 1936 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Survey of History and Natural Sciences of the Five Rivers Area, Undated (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 13)
    - Torreya- With photograph of Schaefer and his Notes, 1933-1934 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 14)
    - Town of Rotterdam Correspondence, 1971 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 15)
    - Trail Walker- Newspaper, 1987-1990 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 16)
    - Trancik, Roger- Hamlets of the Adirondacks, Ithaca, 1983 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 17)
    - Tree Study, Undated (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 18)
    - "Unit Planning for Wilderness Management," VanValkenburgh, Norman J.- The Association for the Protection of the Adirondacks Special Report, 1987 Spring (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 19)
    - Vroman's Nose Preservation Corporation- Financial Report, Annual Meeting Minutes & Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1987-1990 (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 20)
    - Vroman's Nose- Maps, reprinted maps, correspondence, 1978; 1984; Undated (Box 11 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 21)
    - Vroman's Nose Preservation Corporation-Newsletter, 1985-1987 (Box 12 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Vroman's Nose- Reprinted articles,maps, correspondence & photos, 1941-1943; 1984; Undated (Box 12 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Vroman's Nose- Reprints, maps & correspondence, 1933; 1947; 1984; Undated (Box 12 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Waterman, Laura and Guy- "Forest and Crag", 1986 (Box 12 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - An Environmental Survey of the Mohawk River Valley-Waterways '73 Volume 1, 1973 (Box 12 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - An Environmental Survey of the Mohwawk River Valley-Waterways '73 Volume 2, 1973 (Box 12 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - "Whiteface Mountain and Its Easier Ice," Manuscript Fragment, Undated (Box 12 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7)
    - Whiteface Mountain Ski Report, Undated (Box 12 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8)
    - WINN-E-COMAC Club, 1935; 1939; 1942; 1948 (Box 12 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1922-1986; Undated; 8.5
    The photographs in this subseries date from Schaefer's teenage years all the way through his retirement after he left the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center. Having a love and deep respect for the outdoors from a young age, Schaefer participated in organized activities like the Mohawk Valley Hiking Club, but he also incorporated spontaneous outdoor adventures into his busy schedule whenever he could. Sometimes this meant a day or afternoon exploring areas in and around the Capital Region; other times it meant taking time to explore while he was away on business. His work for General Electric, Munitalp, and the State University at Albany/ASRC (not to mention his extensive consulting) offered ample opportunities to venture into mountain ranges, deserts, plains, valleys, and forests to pursue environmental studies that were of interest to him.
    This subseries includes many photo negatives and slides in addition to traditional photographs and are identified as such in their folder titles.
    - Adirondack Trail Club- photos, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Adirondacks-slides, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Augur Falls, Sacandaga River-photos, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Australia- slides, 1961 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Bacteria- photographs, 1968 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Bellata Ranch- negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Big Prairie- negatives, 1953 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7)
    - Birds- photographs, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8)
    - Bonito Lava Flow- negatives, 1963 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9)
    - Bridges- photos, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - California- negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Canandaigua Lake- slides, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Canoeing, 1931 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 13)
    - Canyon Land- negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 14)
    - Cedar Ranch Petrified Wood- slides, 1973 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 15)
    - Clouds and Cloud Formations-slides, 1957-1978 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 16)
    - Colorado River Trips-slides, 1969-1973 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 17)
    - Columbia Gorge-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 18)
    - Crater Lake-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 19)
    - Crater, SP-slides, 1973 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 20)
    - Crystals, Gypsum-photo, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 21)
    - Dams-photos, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 22)
    - Devils Post Pile California-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 23)
    - Devils Tower-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 24)
    - Dewdrops-photos, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 25)
    - Dunes, Sand-photos, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 26)
    - Dust Cloud Mount Saint Helen's-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 27)
    - East-slides, 1977 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 28)
    - East Pocket Ridge-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 29)
    - Edith Park Slash from Clear Cut-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 30)
    - Environmental-slides, 1971 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 31)
    - Farming-photographs, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 32)
    - Fiji Island-slides, 1972 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 33)
    - Five Rivers Rambles-articles, 1971-1972 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 34)
    - Five Rivers Rambles-negatives, 1971-1972 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 35)
    - Fog Woestyne-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 36)
    - Fungus-photo, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 37)
    - Geology-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 38)
    - Giant Mountain-negatives, 1964-1965 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 39)
    - Glacier Park-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 40)
    - Grand Falls-negatives, 1965 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 41)
    - Great Sand Dunes, Colorado-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 42)
    - Great Smokies East-slides, 1976 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 43)
    - Grand Tetons-negatives, 1952 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 44)
    - Great Flats Aquifer-negatives, 1938 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 45)
    - Great Flats Aquifer-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 46)
    - Helderbergs-negatives, 1958-1963 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 47)
    - Helderbergs-negatives, 1958-1963 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 48)
    - Helderbergs-negatives, 1958-1963 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 49)
    - Helderbergs-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 50)
    - Hidden Lakes-photos, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 51)
    - Hiking-negatives, 1952 (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 52)
    - Hiking-negatives, Undated (Box 13 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 53)
    - Hiking-photographs, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Hiking-photographs, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Huyck Preserve-photos, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Ice- slides, 1956-1986 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Ice- slides, 1962-1973 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Ice Cone and Pillar Minelot Falls, Helderbergs, New York-photo, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Ice Stalagmites-photograph, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7)
    - Ice Stalagmites, Tory Cave, Helderberg Mountains-photograph, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8)
    - Ice Storms-negatives, 1964-1972 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9)
    - Indian Ladder Cliffs-photographs, 1931 January (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - Insects-photographs, 1943 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Japan-slides, 1970 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Kings Highway Schenectady, Albany- negatives, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 13)
    - Kings Road Pine Bush-negatives, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 14)
    - Kings Road Vyt Kyck-negatives, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 15)
    - Kunjamuch Cave, Adirondacks-photos, Undated (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 16)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1952-1973 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 17)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1953-1967 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 18)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1954-1976 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 19)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1955-1970 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 20)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1955-1976 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 21-22)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1955-1981 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 23)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1956-1967 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 24)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1956-1978 (Box 14 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 25)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1957-1972 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1957-1974 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1957-1976 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1957-1977 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1958-1967 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1958-1978 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1959-1972 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7-8)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1966 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1968 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1969 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1970 (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962; 1966; Undated (Box 15 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 13)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1972 (Box 16 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1-5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1973 (Box 16 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1974 (Box 16 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7-8)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1975 (Box 16 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9-12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1976 (Box 17 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1-7)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1977 (Box 17 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8-9)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1978 (Box 17 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10-12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1978 (Box 18 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1979 (Box 18 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1984 (Box 18 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1965 (Box 18 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1971 (Box 18 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1972 (Box 18 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6-7)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1974 (Box 18 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1976 (Box 18 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9-12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1976 (Box 19 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1978 (Box 19 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1981 (Box 19 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3-4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962-1972 (Box 19 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962-1974 (Box 19 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962-1976 (Box 19 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7-9)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962-1977 (Box 19 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1972 (Box 19 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1972 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1973 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1974 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1975 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1978 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1979 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1972 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7-9)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1974 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1975 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1976 (Box 20 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1976 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1965-1976 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1965-1984 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1968 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1972 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1974 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1975 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7-8)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1977 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9-10)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1978 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1968-1971 (Box 21 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1968-1975 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1968-1977 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1972-1976 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1972-1977 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4-5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1975-1978 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Lewis Lake-negatives, 1953 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7)
    - Little Lake Cran, MI-slides, Undated (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8)
    - Louisiana-slides, 1971-1972 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9)
    - Mann Gulah Fire Tragedy-photograph of site, 1949 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - Maroon Bells, Colorado-negatives, 1966 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Mesa Verde National Park Colorado, 1922 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Metcalf Lake-negatives, Undated (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 13)
    - Michigan-negatives, 1928 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 14)
    - Mohawk River-slides, 1972-1980 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 15)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club-negatives, 1929-1930 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 16)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club-negatives, 1930-1932 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 17)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club-negatives, 1930-1932 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 18)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club-negatives, 1930-1932 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 19)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club-negatives, 1935-1938 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 20)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club-negatives, 1937 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 21)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club-photos, Undated (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 22)
    - Mohonk Preserve-slides, 1975 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 23)
    - Mohonk Preserve-slides, 1976-1978 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 24)
    - Mohonk Preserve-slides, 1981 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 25)
    - Mohonk Preserve-clouds, 1965-1983 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 26)
    - Montana, Washington State, Oregon- slides, 1948-1965 (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 27)
    - More Heat from your Fireplace- photos, Undated (Box 22 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 28)
    - Mount Rainer-negatives, Undated (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Mountains-negatives, Undated (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Mud-photos, Undated (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Natural History-negatives, Undated (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Nature-photos, Undated (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Nature-photos, Undated (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Nature-photos, 1947-1961 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7)
    - Nature-slides, 1948-1969 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8)
    - Nature-slides, 1948-1986 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9)
    - Nature-slides, 1950-1973 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - Nature-slides, 1951-1973 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Nature-slides, 1952-1972 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Nature-slides, 1954-1973 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 13)
    - Nature-slides, 1960-1976 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 14)
    - Nature-slides, 1964-1981 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 15)
    - Natures-slides, 1981 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 16)
    - Nevada-slides, 1961-1962 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 17)
    - Niagara Falls-negatives, 1964-1965 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 18)
    - Northeast- slides, 1947-1972 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 19)
    - Northeast, USA-slides, 1947-1982 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 20)
    - Northeast- slides, 1949-1970 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 21)
    - Northeast- slides, 1951-1970 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 22)
    - Northeast- slides, 1951-1978 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 23)
    - Northeast- slides, 1952-1970 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 24)
    - Northeast- slides, 1952-1975 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 25)
    - Northeast- slides, 1954-1971 (Box 23 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 26)
    - Northeast- slides, 1954-1973 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Northeast- slides, 1954-1981 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Northeast, USA-slides, 1954-1984 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Northeast- slides, 1955-1976 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Northeast, USA- slides, 1955-1984 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Northeast- slides, 1956-1972 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Northeast, USA- slides, 1964-1984 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7)
    - Northeast, USA- slides, 1966-1983 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8)
    - Northeast, USA- slides, 1966-1984 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9)
    - Northeast, USA- slides, 1967-1976 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - Northeast- slides, 1967-1976 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Northeast- slides, 1967-1987 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Northeast- slides, 1968-1972 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 13)
    - Northeast- slides, 1968-1981 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 14)
    - Northeast- slides, 1969-1976 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 15)
    - Northeast, USA- slides, 1969-1983 (Box 24 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 16)
    - Northeast- slides, 1952-1974 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Northeast- slides, 1970-1981 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Northeast- slides, 1972-1982 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Northeast- slides, 1971-1974; 1979; 1981 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Northeast- slides, 1960-1963; 1971-1973; 1976; 1967-1969 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - Northeast- slides, 1963; 1965; 1968; 1971-1974; 1980 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)
    - Northeast, USA- slides, 1979-1984 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 7)
    - Northeast- slides, 1980-1981 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 8)
    - Northeast, USA- slides, 1981-1984 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 9)
    - Northeast- slides, 1984 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 10)
    - Northwest- slides, 1948; 1953-1956 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 11)
    - Northwest- slides, 1948; 1952-1953; 1969 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 12)
    - Northwest, USA, Mission Mountains and Lake-slides, 1975; 1978 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 13)
    - Northwest, Montana-slides, 1974-1975; 1979 (Box 25 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 14)
    - Oak Creek Black Point-negatives, Undated (Box 26 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 1)
    - Old Erie Canal-negatives, Undated (Box 26 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 2)
    - Olympics-negatives, Undated (Box 26 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 3)
    - Oregon-negatives, Undated (Box 26 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 4)
    - Panama Canal Zone-slides, 1962; 1966 (Box 26 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 5)
    - P4 North-photographs, Undated (Box 26 (8-Environmentalism), Folder 6)